Guide to the Ruth Asawa Papers M1585
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 8. Alvarado Arts Workshop and Alvarado Elementary School, 1964-2002
  - 8.2 photographs
    - Paul Lanier tile mural/mosaic project, 1998-2000 (Box 220, Folder 3)
    - Nancy Thompson butterfly mural (Box 220, Folder 4)
    - miscellaneous murals/mosaics (Box 221, Folder 1, Box 220, Folder 5)
    - slides, visual art (clay/masks/milk carton art) (Box 221, Folder 2)
    - slides, visual art (painting/paper/stained glass) (Box 221, Folder 4)
    - slides, visual art (baker’s clay) (Box 222, Folder 1)
    - slides, visual art (projects) (Box 222, Folder 2)
      banners/wall hangings, costume, batik, paper mache, plaster, prints/etchings, scarecrows, tie dye, sewing, weaving, rugmaking, woodworking.
    - slides, performing arts (dance, music, puppetry, drama) (Box 222, Folder 3)
    - slides, secondary schools (Everett, James Lick) (Box 222, Folder 5)
      Murals, puppets, etc.
    - Mission High School murals (Polytechnic site) (Box 226, Folder 5)
    - slides, Mission High School (Box 223, Folder 1)
      Baker’s clay, drama, campus (old Polytechnic HS), life masks, milk carton art, mime, painting, puppetry, sewing, stained glass, tai chi, woodcarving.
    - slides, miscellaneous events, etc. (Box 223, Folder 2)
      Summer School 1981, exhibitions (Noe Valley Ministry), field trips (1116, foundry, etc.), Schoolworks, Learning Center
    - slides, miscellaneous projects (Box 223, Folder 3)
    - School Works Unlimited (Box 226, Folder 8)
    - photos for Alvarado report, 1998 (Box 223, Folder 4)
    - miscellaneous snapshots (Box 223, Folder 5)
    - Clay Chair project (Box 223, Folder 6)
    - Pinata of Dreams project (Box 223, Folder 7)
    - Christmas in April (Box 223, Folder 8)
    - clay projects, Paul Lanier (Box 224, Folder 1)
    - Carnival (Box 224, Folder 2)
    - Bill Horgas wood carving demo (Box 224, Folder 3)
    - Wendy Nelder (Box 224, Folder 4)
    - Alvarado Revisited photo album (Box 224, Folder 5)
    - field trips- 1116 Castro (Alvarado) (Box 226, Folder 2)
    - origami workshops (Box 225, Folder 1)
  - 8.3 oversize
    - Mosaic General Plan, 1970 (Flat-box 55, Folder 5)
    - Alvarado Art Workshop Grows Up poster, 1982 (Flat-box 55, Folder 10)
      For 14th year anniversary, Ruth Asawa Day. With Nancy Thompson illustration.
    - Alvarado Elementary School New Art Room blueprints, 1994-04-10 (Flat-box 74, Folder 1)
    - Alvarado Workshop Statement of Purpose by Ruth Asawa (Flat-box 78, Folder 10)
    - Schoolworks Unlimited apron (Flat-box 270, Item 1)
      Apron with Schoolworks logo, as sold in the Schoolworks store.
    - Alvarado t-shirt (Flat-box 270, Item 2)
    - Alvarado quilt, 1974 (Box 269)
      Patchwork quilt made by parents, artists and teachers as a gift to Ruth.
  - 8.4 A/V
    - Alvarado Arts Day, 1 videotape(s) (hi-8) (Box 47, Folder 10)
      Arts Day at Alvarado Elementary School
    - Alvarado Class At Castro. Elliot's, 1 videotape(s) (hi-8) (Box 47, Folder 11)
      Alvarado Elementary School field trip to 1116 Castro. Nancy Thompson present. Shot by Terry Schmitt.
    - Edison Alvarado Art P., 1972; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 54, Folder 12)
      Low budget self-produced audio documentary about Alvarado Art Workshop. unidentified speaker, possibly Sally Woodbridge. interview with Alvarado principal McGinnis, teacher Marlyeen Stettner, custodian Matt Swan, artist Nancy Thompson, Edison principal Mr. Sanchez with a second unidentified female speaker. Segments separated by singing children.
    - Evening Show, KPIX. Ruth Asawa, 1977-01-20; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 43, Folder 4)
      0-6:31 news segment with Asawa at Alvarado school making life masks with children. 7:28 interview with Harlem Globetrotters Meadowlark Lemon, Jackie Jackson [possibly raw]
    - Alvarado #1 Carlos; Alvarado #2 Carlos NG [no good?]; Alvarado #3, 1978; 4 audiotape reel(s) (Box 79, Folder 6)
      Raw audio for documentary? interviewing various San Francisco teachers in art, dance, theater, music, gardening, etc. (not just Alvarado). 1a- Carlos Lorca; Elyse Jacobs; unknown speaker; Miranda, Youth Guidance Center; other speakers; [23:58] Ruth Asawa Lanier; Benito Santiago; other speakers -- 1b- recorded music and speech, unknown language. 2a- Carlos Lorca; Barbara Manini; Mary Ann Crandall; George Sams; Sal Steinberg; other speaker -- 2b. electronic sound effects, for theater? 3a- speech, unknown language; [1:06] Ginger Drake, CETA Artist in Residence at Mission HS; [11:47] Ruth Asawa; [26:19] Benito Santiago; [34:04] Carlos Lorca; [43:17] speech, unknown language.
    - Annette Clark AAW Dinner Table, 1997-06-28; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 48, Folder 8)
      Alvarado Arts Workshop reunion gathering hosted by Annette [?], with Ruth Asawa, Nancy Thompson, Dottye Dean, Leah [Forbes?], Trudy Clawson, Andrea Jepson, many others. shot by Terry Schmitt.
    - Alvarado, Nancy Thompson. Terry Schmitt. Mural Project, 1998; 1 videotape(s) (hi-8) (Box 48, Folder 10)
      Nancy Thompson working with children on "Butterfly Gardens" mural at Alvarado Elementary School. Shot by Terry Schmitt.
    - Alvarado. Renegade Recess, 2000-03-15; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 48, Folder 12)
      Ruth and a woodcarver making de Young fundraiser piggybank at Alvarado during recess.
    - Alvarado Mural Installation. Easter Week 2000 / April 2000, 2000-04; 1 videotape(s) (hi-8) (Box 48, Folder 13)
      Alvarado mural installation
    - Each One Teach One. The Alvarado School Art Program. by Valerie Soe and Ruth Asawa, 2002; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 49, Folder 2)
      Professionally produced program on Alvarado Arts Program.
- Series 9. San Francisco School of the Arts, 1973-2012
  The San Francisco School of the Arts, renamed the Ruth Asawa San Francisco School of the Arts in 2010, is a four-year public high school founded by Ruth Asawa and others. SOTA's arts-intensive program within a regular academic context was modeled after NYC's School of Performing Arts, with the Artists-in-Residence concept inherited from the Alvarado Arts Workshop. An arts/alternative magnet school was first discussed in the early 1970s, and Ruth wrote a proposal for a High School For The Creative Arts in 1976, but it really took until Myra Kopf's election to the Board of Education in 1980 for real planning to begin. An ad hoc committee met for a year and a half, and in September 1982 SOTA began with a ninth grade class, adding a class each year until June 1986's first graduating class of 65 seniors.
  As a public school, it relied on San Francisco Unified's administrative support, and SFUSD's well-chronicled difficulties in the 80s and 90s were SOTA's too. To assist with the guiding and fine-tuning of the school's mission, the SOTA Task Force was charged in 1987, and the Laniers were active members. The SOTA Foundation developed from the Alvarado Arts Workshop, in large part to manage fundraising for SOTA. Support came mostly from philanthropic foundations, as well as the NEA, California Arts Council, and local organizations. Ruth was on the Foundation Board from 1980 to 1988 with six years as president. After leaving the foundation, Ruth mostly devoted her SOTA efforts to fundraising and independent site planning.
  SOTA had begun by sharing a campus and many classes with McAteer High School, but in 1985 a concerted effort had begun to find an independent site (one in fact that continues today). In 1992, the district approved a move to 700 Font Boulevard, an unused elementary school across from San Francisco State University. To alleviate some of the moving expenses, students and staff volunteered to renovate the space themselves. The location's proximity to SFSU had advantages, but its remoteness and limited size were problematic. Within a few years, Superintendent Bill Rojas promised SOTA a site at the former SFUSD headquarters at 135 Van Ness, a location central to the Arts District which the school had long campaigned for. After innumerable hurdles, including lawsuits, rising costs, and endless meetings, reports, and disagreements, SOTA in the end chose to return to 555 Portola Drive after McAteer was dissolved in 2002.
  Asawa's SOTA files are relatively comprehensive and there are many copies of correspondence and memoranda that she was not directly involved with. They are chronological for the most part, except for separated administrative files, class files, printed material related to performances and events, Albert Lanier's 135 Van Ness dossier, and others.
  Ruth Asawa San Francisco School of the Arts
  - 9.1 chronological files
    - undated (Box 139, Folder 4)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 139, Folder 5)
    - other alternative/arts/magnet schools, 1975-1998 (Box 139, Folder 3)
    - 1976 (Box 139, Folder 6)
    - 1977 (Box 139, Folder 7)
    - 1978-1982 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - Concept Paper, Articles of Incorporation (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - 1983-1985 (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - 1986-1988 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - SOTA Task Force, 1987-1988 (Box 140, Folders 5-6)
    - 1989 (Box 140, Folder 7)
    - Noh Mask project for Cherry Blossom Festival 1989 (Box 140, Folder 8)
    - Projections In Performance event, 1989 (Box 140, Folder 9)
      Ruth Asawa and Mae Lee developed folded paper sculpture for a SOTA dance performance. Herbert Bielawa did music for the piece.
    - SOTA Art Store, 1989-1990 (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - McAteer ESL (Box 141, Folder 2)
    - 1990 (Box 141, Folder 3)
    - SFUSD/Cortines correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 141, Folder 4)
    - 1991 (Box 141, Folder 5)
    - Long Term Site Committee, 1991-1993 (Box 141, Folder 6)
    - SOTA Task Force Letters of Support, 1990-1992 (Box 141, Folder 7)
    - clippings, 1992 (Box 141, Folder 8)
    - 1992 (Box 142, Folder 1)
    - 1993 (Box 142, Folder 2)
    - site planning, 1994 (Box 142, Folder 3)
    - 1994 (Box 142, Folder 4)
    - NEH proposal for "Imagine: Arts and Humanities" lecture series, 1994-1995 (Box 142, Folder 5)
    - Proposition A Bond (Box 142, Folder 6)
    - 1995 (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - 1996 (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Bill Rojas, 1996-2000 (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - 1997-1999 (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - SOTA Task Force, 1999 (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - 2000 (Box 143, Folder 6)
    - SOTA Task Force, 2000-2001 (Box 143, Folder 7)
    - 2001-2012 (Box 144, Folder 1)
  - 9.2 yearbooks, 1993, 1997 (Box 146, Folder 6)
  - 9.3 student publications: Freestyle Expression, Epiphany, etc. (Box 146, Folder 7)
  - 9.4 PTSA "The Font" newsletter, 1983-1998 (Box 147, Folder 1)
    Formerly "SOTA Parents Association Newsletter," then "The Link"
  - 9.5 student events and performances (non-benefit), 1984-2013 (Box 147, Folder 2)
  - 9.6 gardening (Box 147, Folder 3)
  - 9.7 Governance/Power Struggles (Box 147, Folder 4)
  - 9.8 Artists vs. Teachers (Box 147, Folder 5)
  - 9.9 Asawa light correspondence (Box 147, Folder 6)
  - 9.10 administrative files
    - classes, 1982-1989 (Box 144, Folder 2)
    - classes, 1990-1994 (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - classes, 1995-2004 (Box 144, Folder 4)
    - fundraising – direct mail (Box 144, Folder 5)
    - fundraising – events, benefits, 1982-1998 (Box 144, Folder 6)
    - Event of the Year/National Dance Institute (NDI)/Circus Wagon project, 1986 (Box 144, Folder 7)
    - funding requests, 1982-1989 (Box 145, Folder 1)
    - funding requests, 1990-1992 (Box 145, Folder 2)
    - funding requests, 1993-1997 (Box 145, Folder 3)
    - donors (Box 145, Folder 4)
    - SOTA foundation donors (Box 145, Folder 5)
    - donors: materials, products (Box 145, Folder 6)
    - financial reports and budgets (Box 145, Folder 7)
    - 501c3 master (Box 145, Folder 8)
    - letterhead, other master copies (Box 145, Folder 9)
    - applications, student recruitment (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - artist recruitment (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - artists-in-residence (including Asawa and non-resident guest artists) (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - staff, including PTSA, Foundation (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - alumni (Box 146, Folder 5)
  - 9.11 photographs
    - Font site (before move), 1992 (Box 227, Folder 7)
    - Font site renovation/Workdays, 1992-1994 (Box 228, Folders 1-2)
    - garden/greenhouse (Box 228, Folder 3)
    - 135 Van Ness walkthrough (Box 229, Folder 1)
    - math/paperfolding (Box 229, Folder 2)
    - paperfolding for dance performance "Breathing" (Box 229, Folder 3)
    - Chinese New Year (Box 229, Folder 4)
    - Japanese mask project/Cherry Blossom Festival (Box 230, Folder 1)
    - clay/ceramics projects (Box 230, Folder 2)
      Includes series (probably by Allen Nomura) of Paul Lanier, Jamin Zaigert, others teaching.
    - golf project (Box 230, Folder 3)
    - poinsetta project, 1985 (Box 230, Folder 4)
    - Chantal Decleve drawing class (Box 230, Folder 5)
    - Luis Valdez (Box 230, Folder 6)
    - Jacques D’Amboise (Box 230, Folder 7)
    - field trips (Sacramento, 1116 Castro, Embarcadero, San Jose, Foundry) (Box 231, Folder 1)
    - Creative Arts Summer School, McAteer (Middle School students) (Box 232, Folder 1, Box 231, Folders 2-4)
    - miscellaneous (Box 232, Folder 2)
    - Service Learning, 1996-1997 (Box 232, Folders 3-4, Box 233)
    - SFSU Class and project, 1996-1997 (Box 233, Folders 2-3)
    - slides - dance, music, visual arts, garden (Box 234, Folder 1)
    - slides – events, field trips, meetings, service learning, summer school, McAteer/Font sites (Box 234, Folder 2)
  - 9.12 Albert Lanier SOTA/135 Van Ness files
    - undated (Box 148, Folder 1)
      Includes notebook with notes and sketches by Ruth.
    - 1992-1996 (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 148, Folder 3)
    - SFUSD/Board of Education meetings, 1999-2000 (Box 151, Folder 1)
    - 2000-2002 (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - reports re: 135 Van Ness (Box 149, Folders 2-4, Box 150, Folders 1-2)
      Includes proposals, blueprints, EIR and other site evaluations, etc.
  - 9.13 oversize
    - SOTA Schematic Design [facilities blueprints], 1996-07-31 (Flat-box 55, Folder 4)
      San Francisco Unified School District - Gordon H. Chong & Associates - Castro-Blanco, Piscioneri and Associates.
    - circus wagon drawings for Event of the Year, 1986 (Map-folder 72)
  - 9.14 A/V
    - Jacque Brel. "Jamie's Tape", 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 50, Folder 4)
      Begins with a few minutes of children dancing and pretending to play along with a recording, followed by miscellaneous student-shot footage of SOTA at Font, including rehearsal for a production of Jacques Brel and students and Susan Stauter discussing it.
    - Highlights From The Event Of The Year. 20 Minute Version, 1987-05-09; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 47, Folder 15)
      Highlights from "Event of the Year" at War Memorial. song and dance performance by 350 San Francisco children, with narration by Howard Hesseman.
    - Breathing: Ruth Asawa and Randee Pauvre "Projections in Performance" Theatre Artaud. Wide Shot and Closeup, 1989-12; 2 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 45, Folder 7)
      "Breathing" dance performance featuring SOTA dancers and paperfolded sculpture by Asawa. Tape 1 is dance rehearsal, Tape 2 is the performance, wide shot camera followed by close up.
    - San Francisco Unified School District School of The Arts. From Bach to Bebop & Back Again, 1992; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 41, Folder 15)
      Commercial recording, see j-card for contents.
    - SOTA. Susan Stauter, Lois Gordon, Ruth Asawa. Commonweath Club, 1992-01-07; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 41, Folder 14)
      School of the Arts panel discussion at Commonwealth Club.
    - SOTA. Luis Valdez, 1992-11-13; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 41, Folder 13)
      Opening programs for new home for School of the Arts. Tape 1, Side A, Side B until 5:00: afternoon speech by Luis Valdez; unknown dramatic performance. Tape 2, Side A: Jim Gonzalez introduces principal Yvonne McClune, Commissioner Carlotta Portillo, [7:25] Ruth Asawa [presenting bronze lifecast to Valdez], Luis Valdez
    - SOTA. Introduction to the San Francisco School of the Arts, 1993-01-26; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 47, Folder 17)
      1. KTVU news story on first day of school at SOTA at Font. Ruth seen briefly 2. "On Our Own" SOTA promo pitch produced by Media Arts Department
    - SFSU Class. Uncatalogued [mostly SOTA performances], 1996; 1 videotape(s) (hi-8) (Box 47, Folder 8)
      School of the Arts Expo event with various performances Poetry, dance, music, drama; [1:47:14] San Francisco State art class
    - SOTA. Jacques D'Amboise. Fisk Video Productions, 1996-02-28; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 48, Folder 1)
      D'Amboise dance workshop at SOTA 1996. 33:06 ends abruptly.
    - SFCCH [SF Community Convalescent Hospital]] Mural. SOTA Field Trip, 1997-03; 1 videotape(s) (hi-8) (Box 48, Folder 6)
      SOTA field trip to mural under construction at SF Community Convalescent Hospital. Nancy Thompson, Isabelle Mixon, others (possibly not Ruth Asawa). content ends 42:50, camera kept recording
    - SOTA Mural Dedication [SF Community Convalescent Hospital], 1997-04-11; 1 videotape(s) (hi-8) (Box 48, Folder 5)
      Mural opening at SF Community Convalescent Hospital. Nancy Thompson, Susan Stauter, Sumiko Kawashima, Isabelle Mixon (whose self-portraits are part of mural), singing students. Ruth Asawa and Albert Lanier are present but don't speak.
    - Jacques D'Amboise at SOTA. Dance, 1998; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 48, Folder 3)
      D'Amboise dance workshop at SOTA.
    - Face Masks at Clarendon Oct. 98; Jacques D'Ambois at SOTA 98; Alvarado Cleanup 11/7/98, 1998; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 48, Folder 9)
      Life maskmaking at school, 39:47 D'Amboise class [duplicate]; 48:10 school cleanup
    - SOTA. Lawrence Hamilton, Male Lead in "Ragtime." 700 Font Blvd., 2000-10-13; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 49, Folder 1)
      Actor Lawrence Hamilton and SOTA drama teacher(?) on stage talking.
- Series 10. Ruth Asawa Fund, 1995-2002
  The Ruth Asawa Fund was incorporated in December 1995 as a 501(c)3 organization "to bring art and artists to the children of San Francisco" by soliciting and channeling financial contributions to arts education in the city. In November 1995, Asawa, as co-chair of the School Of The Arts' Service Learning in the Arts Ad Hoc Committee, successfully submitted a proposal to the Miranda Lux Foundation for a Service Learning Pilot Project which resulted in $15,000 awarded to the Ruth Asawa Fund early the next year, and service learning was the first major Fund project. The Fund also provided life drawing models to SOTA and brought guest teachers such as Jacques D’Amboise and Toby Klayman. Most files consist of correspondence with and reports to various foundations, especially Philanthropic Ventures. In general these files were less organized than the rest of the collection, and many files related to SOTA, Alvarado, the Youth Arts Festival, and other projects and workshops, some predating the Fund, can be found here.
  - announcement, thank you notes (Box 151, Folder 2)
  - office conversation notes (Box 151, Folder 3)
  - Vashti Becktell (administrative assistant) (Box 151, Folder 4)
  - board, 1998-2000 (Box 151, Folder 5)
  - Daniel Roth (Box 151, Folder 6)
  - Susan Stauter (Box 151, Folder 7)
  - artists-in-residence resumes (Box 151, Folder 8)
  - calendars (Box 151, Folder 9)
  - budget, fundraising, 1995-1997 (Box 151, Folder 10)
  - Brian Asawa recital fundraiser, 1997 (Box 151, Folder 11)
  - fundraising appeal, 2000 (Box 151, Folder 12)
  - Bothin Foundation (Box 152, Folder 1)
  - Fleishhacker Foundation (Box 152, Folder 2)
  - Haas Fund (Box 152, Folder 3)
  - McKesson Foundation (Box 152, Folder 4)
  - Miranda Lux Foundation (Box 152, Folder 5)
  - Philanthropic Ventures Foundation, 1991-2001 (Box 152, Folders 6-8)
  - Louise and Claude Rosenberg, Jr. Family Foundation, 1992-2001 (Box 152, Folder 9)
  - San Francisco Foundation (Box 152, Folder 10)
  - Shinnyo-en Foundation (Box 152, Folder 11)
  - Wallace Alexander Gerbose Foundation (Box 152, Folder 12)
  - Wells Fargo Foundation, Libby Dietrich, consultant (Box 152, Folder 13)
  - PVF Report, 1995 (Box 153, Folder 1)
  - report material, 1996-1997 (Box 153, Folder 2)
  - PVF Report, 1995-1996 (Box 153, Folder 3)
  - Documentation Project Proposal, 1997-05 (Box 153, Folder 4)
  - PVF Report, 1997 (Box 153, Folder 5)
  - Wells Fargo Report/Background Information (Box 153, Folder 6)
  - report material, 1998-2000 (Box 153, Folder 7)
  - report photographs, 1998 (Box 153, Folder 8)
  - report, 1999 (Box 153, Folder 9)
  - thank you letters (Box 153, Folder 10)
  - Service Learning (Box 153, Folder 11)
  - SOTA, 1997-2001 (Box 154, Folder 1)
  - Alvarado School (Box 154, Folder 2)
  - Deck The Hall event, Davies Symphony Hall (origami decorations), 1996 (Box 154, Folder 3)
  - Magic Theatre, 1997-1998 (Box 154, Folder 4)
  - Neighborhood Beautification Fund Project / Eureka Valley Trails and Art Network, 1998-2002 (Box 154, Folder 5)
  - correspondence, 1996 (Box 154, Folder 6)
  - correspondence, 1997 (Box 154, Folder 7)
  - correspondence, 1998 (Box 154, Folder 8)
  - correspondence, 1999 (Box 154, Folder 9)
  - correspondence, 2000-2002 (Box 154, Folder 10)
- Series 11. Education and Schools, General
  - 11.1 educational correspondence (Box 97, Folder 5)
    Correspondence not easily absorbed by any other series. Majority are from Asawa to such people as Bill Honig and State Assemblyman John Vasconcellos. Subjects include educational reform, the SFUSD, the Board of Education, the Feingold Snack Program, etc. Also included are some editorials and inquiries from arts educators.
  - 11.2 educational resources (Box 98, Folders 1-4)
    Articles, reports, pamphlets, etc. concerning arts education, educational reform, and the San Francisco Unified School District. See also clipping files on education and art education.
  - 11.3 photographs, other school/youth art projects
    - origami/paper folding (Box 225, Folder 2)
    - baker’s clay projects (Box 225, Folder 3)
    - field trips - 1116 Castro, Jamin Zegart and class (Box 226, Folder 3)
    - puppetry (Box 226, Folder 4)
      Includes Chinese puppet show at 1116 Castro.
    - James Lick projects (Box 226, Folder 6)
    - Clarendon dragon project (Box 226, Folder 7)
    - Oroville, California projects (Box 226, Folder 9)
    - "Ceasefire" peace murals, Golden Gate Park (Box 226, Folder 10)
    - Youth Guidance Center (Box 227, Folder 1)
    - McKinley tile mural, etc. (Box 227, Folder 3)
    - face casting, Malcolm X, 1989 (Box 227, Folder 4)
    - painting, Rooftop, 1995 (Box 227, Folder 5)
    - miscellaneous projects (Box 224, Folder 6)
      Includes Alaska 1975, Japanese Cultural Center cleanup.
    - slides, miscellaneous school/youth projects (Box 227, Folder 6)
    - oversize (Flat-box 241, Folder 1)
  - 11.4 oversize
    - Map of The City and County of San Francisco Unified School District, 1971 (Map-folder 65)
    - Jim Schermerhorn sketches of Rooftop Elementary school kids on playground [brochure for children's organization] (Map-folder 57)
  - 11.5 A/V
    - All Things Considered #821018. Arts Cutaway, 1982; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 40, Folder 11)
      NPR All Things Considered radio program about public school of the arts in New York City.
    - Schools [Class Action: A Town Hall," KQED video], 1991; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 47, Folder 3)
      "Class Action: A Town Hall" KQED Channel 9 panel discussion on state of California public schools
- Series 12. Student Art and Correspondence
  - 12.1 artist books (Box 157, Folders 1-3, Box 158, Folder 1)
    Unknown origin, but probably from an adult workshop.
  - 12.2 calendars, 1972-2002 (Box 158, Folder 2)
  - 12.3 printmaking (Box 158, Folder 3)
  - 12.4 SFUSD Creative Arts Summer School project report, 1991 (Box 158, Folder 4)